VIMAL VINAYRAJ

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Email - vimalvinayraj@gmail.com
WhatsApp / Phone - +971521998939
LinkedIn- https://www.linkedin.com/in/vimal-vinayraj-085338189/
Website- https://vimalvinayrajcom.netlify.app/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software professional with 5+ years of experience as a Frontend Engineer designing and developing large-scale applications across organizations. Experience in developing ReactJS and VueJS based web applications. Extensive experience in website development using WordPress, HTML, CSS and UI/UX design technologies. Proven experience in infrastructure set-up, application management and providing quick and efficient solutions to product development. Outstanding team player with high determination to achieve targets.

SKILLS

*	HTM	L.	CSS.	JS
**	H I W	L,	CSS.	J١

❖ TypeScript, VueJS, ReactJS

♦ GIT

♦ Styled components

❖ UI/UX design

* Responsive web design

CSS Grid, Flexbox

❖ WordPress

❖ Adobe XD

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

1. WoodPecker Data Analysis · Dubai · UAE

VUE Frontend Developer, June 2022 – Present

Responsible for the front-end development and maintenance of the H5/Web side of the company's projects. Project: KG-Sport (Web & Mobile)

- Created UI interfaces & functionalities for user websites.
- Developed User interface, Mobile/H5 designs with Vueis framework.
- Collaborated with back-end team members to implement feature updates.
- Integrating the front end using the API data from the backend.
- Involved with bug fixing on functionality, performance and designing issues with Javascript and Vue3js.
- Supported the QA team to design test cases for various change requests and enhancement.
- Undertook various responsibilities in a job which requires good coding, problem resolution and communication skills.
- To test websites during the development process for usability and fixing bugs.
- Ensure that the website front-end is free from errors or bugs.
- To supervise the production and maintenance of the user interfaces of websites.

2. Up Works · Dubai · UAE

Freelancer, Feb 2022 - June 2022

- I offer my services to entrepreneurs and organizations.
- Freelancing gave me the opportunity to take on responsibility for the UX and design side of applications also.

3. Discovery Group of Companies · Sharjah · UAE

Website Developer, Jan 2018 – Jan 2022

- Design, develop website and add more appealing features.
- Designed concepts using AdobeXD.
- Converted PSD/AdobeXD to HTML.
- Created websites and reusable components.
- Translated the design into UI and built it as React components.
- Redesigned sections of the website to ensure a more attractive and user-friendly experience.
- Maintained and updated code as needed.
- Used WordPress, HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript to develop websites that are compatible between all browsers.

4. Diya Systems Pvt Ltd· Mangalore· India

Web Administrator, Jan 2015–Jan 2017

Responsible for the services in front-end website hosting company as per client requirement.

- Developing website as per client requirement under instruction of Project Manager which includes static website.
- CMS application installation help like WordPress, Prestashop, Joomla etc.
- Create HTML email templates.
- Designed custom graphics and guided clients with various SEO features and implemented them in website.
- Having strong management skills to work efficiently with web designers, UI developers & other team members.
- Accessing Mysql databases and edit the tables for client as per requirement.

EDUCATION

• BSC Computer Science - Swami Vivekananda University

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

ASTROLABS · Dubai · UAE

- Develop full-stack web applications to analyze and process data.
- Ensure applications security and ability to interact with multiple APIs and databases.
- Create frontend with **ReactJs**, server-side architecture with wide range of technologies, including **NodeJs**, **ExpressJs**, and **MongoDB**.
- Gained hands-on expertise in **MaterialUI**, Nodejs, Express and similar back-end Node.js as well asfront-end presentation frameworks web application frameworks.
- Work closely with project development team, developers to determine problems, troubleshooting, and best practices.

•

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Languages: English, Hindi, Malayalam and basic Arabic Languages.
- Nationality: India.
- Availability: Immediately available.